Sr. Network Engineer

Sr. Network Engineer - Department of Health and Human Services

Clairton, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/fbc9a84215eb37e7

To acquire a senior network position that will utilize my 15 year career in the Information Technology field and leverage my leadership skills, experience and education in contributing to the profitable growth of an organization.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Network Engineer

Department of Health and Human Services - Rockville, MD - October 2013 to Present

Employed as a senior Network Engineer supporting the Department of Health and Human Services' Health Resources & Services Administration. My primary responsibilities included IOS upgrading, configuration and maintenance of Cisco switches throughout the enclave. Evaluation of existing systems and departmental needs to configure, analyze and implement for out of band management. Selected accomplishments included:

- Upgrade of Cisco network equipment (3750 stacked and 3560's) for the agency's infrastructure.
- Implemented, analyzed and recommended appropriate system for the out of band management monitoring. utilizing Solarwinds for primary and disaster recovery site.
- Monitored and responded to network anomalies utilizing Solarwinds/Orion's software and recommended appropriate network solutions for issues.

Department of Justice

FBI Headquarters - Washington, DC - June 2012 to August 2013

Sr. Network Engineer

Employed as a senior Network Engineer supporting the Department of Justice's Federal Bureau of Investigation's Headquarters. My primary responsibilities included configuration and maintenance of Cisco switches and routers. Creating and maintaining network diagrams, documentation and configurations for classified and unclassified networks. Evaluated existing systems and users needs to analyze, design, recommend, and implement system changes as needed by Bureau directives. Selected accomplishments included:

- Applied creative approaches and innovative thinking to the design of a new and enhanced customer network architecture utilizing Microsoft Visio.
- · Researched, developed, tested and documented unclassified and classified network designs.
- Analyzed and recommended appropriate network upgrades to support future requirements.
- Managed customer timelines and deliverables to help facilitate successful engineering project activities throughout the Bureau. Worked in conjunction with senior management to align IT programs with the functional business units of the agency.

Sr. Network Engineer

Dell Services Federal Government - Fairfax, VA - February 2009 to September 2012

Employed as a senior Network Engineer supporting the Department of Defense's Business Transformation Agency. Main responsibilities included configuration and maintenance of Cisco switches, routers and VPN. Managed firewall modifications and network traffic security policies using Sidewinder. Scheduled shifts

for junior network engineers and support staff to ensure operations. Required to maintain a 6 am to 6 pm environment, achieving the goal of 99.999% network uptime over the course of FY10. Selected accomplishments included:

- Management of Web proxy and external SPAM filtering administration/maintenance/troubleshooting.
- Upkeep and management for web filtering and gateway security utilizing Secure Computing Smart Filter.
- Configuration, installation, and maintenance of enclave wireless network under DoD guidelines
- Information Assurance Management for DoD Agency following 8750-1 guidelines
- Performed security audits and developed training for IA security awareness programs
- Validate IA Controls and verify DISA STIGS have been met utilizing and array of network analyzing tools (i.e. REM Retina, GOLD DISK, HBSS and SCRI)
- Worked in conjunction with senior management to align IT programs with the functional business unit's of the agency
- Wrote and implemented project plans for network equipment upgrades to include IOS, CatOS image upgrades, and configuration changes
- Perform duties of the Information Assurance Manager for reacting to and tracking IAVM's, POA&M, and DIACAP package status for ATO accreditation
- Agency Lead for IDS notification and remediation, in conjunction with ARL CNDSP, for incident violations
- Gold Disk to assist junior Systems Administrators/Engineers with accrediting new systems and updating VMS/eMASS as required
- Perform regular backups and ensured that backups were moved to offsite location
- · Assisted with draft and deployment of server hardware architecture

Senior Network Engineer, Manager

Sirius XM Satellite Radio - Washington, DC - October 2006 to January 2009

Employed as a Senior Network Engineer for Sirius XM radio, main responsibilities included tier 3 solutions for layer 2 and 3 environment switching. Drafted and implemented ACL security policies. Spearheaded the network scaling, expansion and infrastructure development of the in house network. Responsible for providing next generation solutions to senior management. Selected accomplishments included:

- Day to day support for 1200 user network environment in 8 national and international remote sites.
- Management of wireless hardware and software for the installation of company WLAN. This included corporate headquarters in Washington, DC and an auxiliary site (CIO and IT staff) in Fairfax, VA
- Managed contractors for stand up of secondary office in Fairfax, VA (complete infrastructure build out from bare bone structure to IT staff environment which included all network, telephony, data and tele-presence conferencing for 240 users)
- Managed resources for re-cabling of copper and fiber (900 plus runs) for main campus office
- Supervised contracted staff for the expansion of data and VoIP capabilities (1600 network drops and 500 VoIP phones)
- Supervised Contracted Staff for the Datacenter Fiber and Copper expansion project (33% increase)
- Provided backup, restored and migrated databases for required application upgrades
- Configuration of f5 BIGip to provide load balancing for development and production farms
- Built and maintained Visio documentation database of network technology
- · Researched solutions for network scalability to include cloud backup services and forensic data recovery
- Processed and implement firewall change request for national and international production and test environments

Network Engineer

Children's Hospital of Pittsburgh - Pittsburgh, PA - September 1998 to March 2006

Employed as a fulltime network engineer supporting the Children's Hospital of Pittsburgh. Primary duties included ensuring HIPPA certification requirements implementation and compliance. Managed layer 2 and 3 switching and routing via command line interface. Responsible for maintaining network availability during disasters on call 24 hours. Selected accomplishments:

- Project Lead in conversion of 3Com infrastructure to Cisco backboned network at CHP main campus and 7 remote sites
- Performed routine and required server maintenance (backups, virus definitions, security patching)
- Installed and configured wireless network and The project included the entire hospital and 3 offsite locations
- Primary support Vocera wireless Communications Project. This included the design, site survey and the installation of Air Monitoring defense devices.
- Installed & maintained 25 Cisco 4506 switches, 40 3550's and 90 wireless 1210 access points via CLI
- Configuration of VLAN's, trunking, QoS and other CCNA level duties
- Monitoring, testing and troubleshooting hardware and software issue pertaining to the LAN and WLAN
- Network administration for documentation and support of 2000 plus user/device environment

Group IT Specialist

Beverly HealthCare - Fort Smith, AR - August 1997 to September 1998

Provided consultation for a national healthcare institution by providing support for 44 distributed nursing homes throughout Pennsylvania. Acted as the primary POC for networking and systems issues. Worked in conjunction with management to outline future technologies and expansion. Selected accomplishments:

- Performed support for all system/network upgrades, installations and development
- Responsible for 44 sites day to day operational status of the network and systems. 24 x 7 onsite support.
- Administered account creation, group policy and conduct audits throughout the Western Pennsylvania region.
- Responsible for the management and configuration of computers and peripheral devices
- Actively tested nextgen solutions for network improvement with corporate headquarters

Network Lab Administrator

North Hills Junior High - Pittsburgh, PA - August 1995 to August 1997

Maintained multiple computer labs for faculty and student use. Duties were mainly centered on lab maintenance and upkeep Selected accomplishments:

- Maintained Macintosh computer lab and trained student and staff use
- Installed new Macintosh computers and peripheral equipment as required

Database Administrator

United Way of Pittsburgh - Pittsburgh, PA - February 1995 to August 1995

Performed database administration in legacy dbase 3 in the development of "Where to Turn" book project. Key contributions:

- Created and updated master database as required
- Performed regular maintenance to include indexing, backups, query routines.
- Conduct quality control on all entries in the "Where to Turn" for publication

Primary Duty - Cable Splicer and Installer at Base Telephone at Marine Corps Base Camp Pendleton

United States Marine Corps - Camp Pendleton, CA - February 1984 to October 1988

Camp Pendleton, CA

Primary Duty - Cable Splicer and Installer at Base Telephone at Marine Corps Base Camp Pendleton

EDUCATION

American History

Duquesne University June 1990 to December 1994

Cable Splicer School at Sheppard Air Force Base - Wichita Falls, TX March 1985 to December 1985

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

Technical:

OS: Cisco CLI, Server 2k3,2K8 MS Windows\Apple OS, working knowledge of Linux

Tools: Citrix/Cisco VPN, , McAfee ePol suite, Army Gold Disk, Retina Security scanner, NetStumbler and Flying Squirrel, McAfee HIPS agent, TCP/IP suite, DHCP/DNS, ePOL IDS host based and network,

Hardware: CISCO Routers (72xx, 65xx, 37xx, 28xx and 25xx series) CISCO Switches (65xx, 45xx, 37xx stacked, and 36xx and 24xx) management, CISCO ACS (3.0), f5 BIGip configuration and maintenance.

Routing Protocols: (BGP, OSPF, EIGRP and RIP)

Leadership: Project Management, team lead, teamwork, strong communication skills, customer service and technical writing.